

ASHOKA B

Jr Data Scientist

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Python NumPy Pandas

SQL Tableau Seaborn

Matplotlib

Scikit-learn

Machine Learning

NLTK

Deep Learning

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (VTU) 2012-16

CERTIFICATION

PG Diploma in Data Science Program from Vidhya Global Academy.

PERSONAL DETAILS

DOB : 5th Nov 1993

Relationship : Single

Nationality : Indian

Languages : English, Hindi,

Kannada, Telugu

CONTACT DETAILS



+91 9611816904



ashoka.51193@gmail.com



S/o Pampanna B, Shridharagadde, Bellary Tq & Dist, Karnataka - 583 103

ABOUT ME

Data Scientist candidate with excellent statistical Knowledge and the ability to identify fine points of data in a sea of information. Well-versed in Statistics and scientific research. Able to process new data and communicate it effectively to lay individuals.

TECHNICAL SKILL

- Analyzing large volumes of data and Sourcing, Cleaning, Manipulating.
- Experience in using well-established supervised and unsupervised machine learning methods for large industry-strength data analysis problems.
- Strong applied statistics skills with a good understanding of statistical testing and their associated pitfalls.
- Basic knowledge of visualization tools such as Tableau and Powe BI.
- Good experience in handling Machine Learning algorithm such are Logistic Regression, Linear regression, KNN, Naive Bayes, Support Vector Machine, Decision tree, Random Forest, GBDT, K-Means Clustering, Hierarchical Clustering, DBSCAN Clustering.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Miraco IT Services Pvt Ltd | Aug 2019 - Present

Jr Data Scientist

Project Title: E-Commerce Products Recommendation using NLP Techniques

- Designing and developing of real time recommendation engine to suggest similar products and upsell opportunities in website.
- The data set had 1.5 millions products, with each having its description in a textual format.
- The raw data was pre-processed and filtered using Natural Language Processing techniques.
- A ML model was developed to identify similar products using text similarity
- For the similarity metric a threshold value was set to identify Top-10 similar items for every product.
- Incoming customer traffic and the increase in purchases were monitored to analyze the model performance

Project Title: Customer Segmentation for Discount Prediction

- The project consisted of multiple ML use-cases related to Real Estate domain.
- The primary among them was to segment the customers to offer discount on package purchases.
- The preprocessing included missing value treatment, data filtration, outlier removal and duplicate data identification using multiple approaches.
- Feature engineering with respect to use case was done by using RFM Analysis approach.
- The customers were sorted using multiple engineered features.
- Business approved thresholds were assigned to the data to extract multiple customer clusters.
- The discount distribution was done to the customers based on the cluster analysis.

Quantity Analyst

BBW Pvt Ltd | Sep 2016 - June 2019

Determining the optimal sequence of operations of the project, whilst implementing efficient methods to increase productivity. Analysis of the project data to plan the upcoming course of activities.